# **Ignacio Suav Mas**

July 15,1985

Email: ignacio.suay@gmail.com **Mobile:** 07511294910 Web: http://www.ignaciosuay.com/

Address: Flat74. 6 Rossetti road. CV online: http://www.ignaciosuav.com/cv **GitHub:** https://github.com/ignacioSuay London, SE16 3EZ

#### **SUMMARY**

Ignacio Suay is a software engineer with 8 years of industry experience in building end-to-end web applications with Java, Spring, Hibernate, AngularJS and many other software technologies.

Currently, he is working with the Worldwide Anti-malarial Resistance Network (WWARN) at the University of Oxford providing the much-needed comprehensive, timely, quality-assured intelligence needed to track the emergence and spread of malaria drug resistance.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

University of Oxford – WorldWide Antimalarial Resistance Network

03/2014 - Present Oxford, UK

# **Senior Software Engineer**

- Develop web applications, end to end, with Java, Hibernate and Spring (Data, MVC and Security)
- Implement front-end user interfaces using GWT, JavaScript and AngularJS.
- Design and maintain Relational Databases
- Design and implement Open source Framework for data visualization
- Help the team achieve the goals as Scrum master
- Supervise junior software developers

Allocate Software - Realtime Health

**Integration Software Engineer** 

10/2012 - 03/2014

Oxford, UK

- Design, develop, test, implement, maintain, support and code enhancements to HL7 interfaces.
- Healthcare software development using Java, Spring, Hibernate and Flex.
- Integration Interfaces with Apache Camel, ActiveMO and CXF Web Services.
- Technical documentation for all phases of integration: analysis, design, development, unit testing, integration testing and go-live support.
- Agile Software development for healthcare.

# Brain Research Imaging Centre - University Of Edinburgh

03/2012 - 10/2012

Edinburgh UK

#### **Data Analyst**

- EEG data analysis
- Lineal Algebra in computational biomedical data.
- Outliers detection in multivariate data.
- Principal Components Analysis (PCA).
- Iterative Re-weighted Least Square.

# Institute of Robotics and Information Technology

10/2007 - 09/2010 Valencia, Spain

#### **Software Engineer**

Web application reporter in traffic mortality accidents using Java, Flex, Spring and Hibernate.

- Statistical Analysis of traffic accidents in Spain using R.
- Database quality web application tool.
- Statistical Yearbook of traffic accidents in Spain

**Engineers Without Borders** 

10/2006 - 10/2007

#### Volunteer Engineer

Valencia, Spain

SOFTWARE SKILLS		
Programming Languages:	Databases:	Environment:
- Java	- MySQL	- Agile Software development
- JavaScript	- MongoDB	- Test-driven development
- SQL	- Oracle	- Behavior driven development
Front-End Technologies:	- H2	- Jenkins CI
- AngularJS	Back-End Technologies:	- Tomcat
- Google Web Toolkit	- Spring (Boot, JPA, Security, MVC Rest)	- Git
- Bootstrap	- Maven	- Jetty
- Compass and CSS	- Hibernate	- Amazon Web Services EC2
- Grunt, Gulp and Bower	- Elasticsearch	- Gerrit Core Review
- HTML5	- Web services (SOAP and REST)	- Linux/Mac Os
- Karma and Jasmine	- Apache Camel	
	- JUnit, TestNG and Mockito	

# **PROJECTS**

# Jira to Word

Web application for exporting data from Jira to Microsoft Word.

## Technology stack:

- Databases: MongoDB and H2
- Java, Spring Boot, Data JPA, MVC REST
- Responsive Web design with Bootstrap, Compass and CSS
- AngularJS and HTML5
- Bower, Gulp and Karma

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

# Maps Surveyor Framework

Maps Surveyor is a mapping platform for visualising data to support statistical reporting, public health surveillance, and health research. It is an Open Source Framework used by different projects like the K13 Surveyor or the Malaria Molecular Surveyor.

#### Technology stack:

- Google Web ToolKit and Bootstrap in the client side
- Java and Remote Procedure Calls in the server side
- Apache Lucene Core search engine

CERTIFICATIONS	
Oracle 1Z0-898 Java Persistence API Developer Certified Expert	03/2016
MongoDB M101J: MongoDB for Java Developers	03/2015
Oracle 1Z0-047 Oracle Database SQL expert Certification	07/2012

Polytechnic University of Valencia and University of Valencia Biomedical Engineering, Master Degree	09/2010 - 09/2012 (First Class Honours)
University of Valencia Computer Engineering, Bachelor's Degree	09/2003 - 07/2009 (First Class Honours)
University of Valencia Telecommunications Engineer Telematics, Bachelor's Degree	09/2003 - 07/2009 (First Class Honours)